fafsa.gov 2013-11-05

# Privacy - FAFSA on the Web - Federal Student Aid

> Privacy Act
> 
> Non-personal information we record
> 
> Security and Intrusion Detection
> 
> Information from e-mail you send us
> 
> Information collected if you complete a form on our Web sites
> 
> State Certification
> 
> Your rights under the Paperwork Reduction Act
> 
> More about privacy and your student aid records
> 
> Privacy Notice
> 

**Privacy Act**

Thank you for visiting our Web site. Our privacy policy is simple: We collect no personal information about you unless you choose to provide that information to us. 

Below you will find information explaining how your information will be safeguarded.

Return to top

**Non-personal information we record**

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the Web site, read pages, or download information, our Web site's operating system will automatically record some general information about your visit. 

During your visit, our Web operating system will record:

1\. The **Internet domain** for your Internet service, such as "xcompany.com" or "xcompany.net" if you use a private Internet access     account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a college or university domain.  
2\. The **type of browser** (such as "Internet Explorer version X") that you are using.  
3\. The **type of operating system** that you use (such as Macintosh, UNIX, or Windows).  
4\. The **date and time** you visit our site, and the Web pages that you visit on our site.   
5\. The **address of the previous Web site** you were visiting, if you linked to us from another Web site.

We use this information for statistical analysis, to help us make our site more useful to visitors. This tracking system does not record information about individuals.

Return to top

**Security and Intrusion Detection**

For security purposes and to make sure this service remains available to all users, we use special software programs for monitoring network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise to cause damage to this government computer system. These programs collect no personally identifiable information, but they do collect information that could help us identify someone attempting to tamper with this Web site. 

Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, we make no other attempts to identify individual users or their usage habits. We only use raw monitoring data logs for determining trends in usage patterns and in diagnosing system problems.

Return to top

**Information from e-mail you send us**

If you decide to send us an electronic mail message (e-mail, which includes information you send to Customer Service regarding a problem or feedback you provide on a Customer Survey), the message will usually contain your return e-mail address. If you include personally identifying information in your e-mail because you want us to address issues specific to your situation, we may use that information in contacting other federal agencies or our partners (such as schools, lenders, or state agencies) in connection with your student aid application or aid awards. In other limited circumstances, including requests from Congress or other parties, we may be required by law to disclose information that you submit. 

Also, e-mail is not necessarily secure against interception. If your communication is very sensitive, or includes personal information such as data from your tax return or student loan account, you may prefer to mail it by postal mail to:

Federal Student Aid Information Center  
P.O. Box 84  
Washington, D.C. 20044 

Return to top

**Information collected if you complete a form on our Web sites**

On this Web site, we offer interactive forms that allow you to apply for financial aid. When you apply for federal student aid using one of these forms, the Office of Federal Student Aid is authorized to maintain a record of the transactions related to your application. 

Under the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended we are allowed to ask for the information on this form so that we can determine whether you are eligible for aid, and, if so, how much. We will share the information with other agencies, such as the Social Security Administration, to verify the information you put on the application. If you do not give us all of the information we need to process your FAFSA, your aid may be delayed or denied. For a complete description of the information we must tell you under the Privacy Act (Your Privacy Act Rights), click the Privacy Act link below.

[Your Privacy Act Rights](javascript:Help\('ffpriv00.htm', 'en_US'\);)

Return to top

**State Certification**

When you submit this application, you are automatically applying for financial aid from your state of legal residence and, in some cases, the state in which your school is located. You are giving your state financial aid agency permission to verify information on this form and to obtain income tax information for all people who are required to report income on this form. 

Return to top

**Your rights under the Paperwork Reduction Act**

According to the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995, no persons are required to respond to a collection of information unless such collection displays a valid OMB control number, which for this form is 1845-0001. Public reporting burden for this collection of information is estimated to average 55 minutes for applicants who use _FAFSA on the Web_ to complete and submit the application, an average of 45 minutes for an applicant who has previously used _FAFSA on the Web_ and completes a renewal FAFSA, and an average of 10 minutes to make FAFSA corrections; these averages include time for reviewing instructions, searching existing data sources, gathering and maintaining the data needed, and completing and reviewing the collection of information. The obligation to respond to this collection is voluntary. Send comments regarding the burden estimate or any other aspect of this collection of information, including suggestions for reducing this burden, to the Federal Student Aid Information Center, P.O. Box 84, Washington, D.C. 20044.

We may request additional information from you to process your application more efficiently. We will collect this additional information only as needed and on a voluntary basis. 

Return to top

**More about privacy and your student aid records**

When you apply for federal student aid, the Office of Federal Student Aid Programs is authorized to maintain a record of the transactions related to your application. 

Click this link to review the System of Records notices, which list the authorized disclosures and the safeguards for the Office of Federal Student Aid Program systems under the [ Privacy Act of 1974, as amended](http://www.usdoj.gov/opcl/privstat.htm). 

If you have authorized us to share your financial aid information with state agencies or the schools that you are thinking of attending, they will also store that information (often in electronic form). State agencies and schools also collect other information relating to financial aid payments, admission, enrollment, etc. The privacy of these records is protected by the [ Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act](http://www.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html). 

Return to top
